CHAITANYA UTTARWAR

#501, 271, Lester Street, N2L3W6, Waterloo, ON | (H) 5483336319 | chaitanyauttarwar046@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Seasoned Java and database developer with more than 2.5 years of experience in fast-paced agile development. Excellent Programming and research skills. Track record of achieving exceptional results in consuming RESTful services and Automation.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, C, C++, JavaScript,
 Technology: Spring Framework, Maven, CSS, HTML, PHP, React
- **Databases:** MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Microsoft Azure
- Dialogflow, UiPath, Automation Anywhere, Katalon
- Tools: Git, Jenkins, Jira, Postman, SoapUl, Latex

Experience

01/2020 to Present **Full Stack Developer**

Manulife Financials – Waterloo, ON, Canada

- Designed and Modified critical stored procedures responsible for loading employee data into the database weekly. This ensured the weekly process takes less than half time to be completed.
- Was a main contributor in running the Manulife Pulse check system which enables the leadership and peers to provide feedback for their colleagues.
- Designed and developed multiple features for various Internal apps in react and made sure it merges well with main app without affecting its latency.
- Coded and tested multiple database APIs to be consumed by the applications hosted on Pivotal cloud foundry.
- Worked extensively on Katalon scripts to ensure the automation to send and collect feedback for the pulse check is done smoothly and quickly.
- Redesigned, Modified and made new tables to accommodate the database scaling.
- Worked on various triggers to ensure the data integrity between tables is maintained. This not only took down manual work but also made sure the data between tables is well updated and error free.
- Maintained the repository with standard version controlling methods and taught the same to the team.
- Completely automated an internal process using Katalon scripts which now needs minimal human intervention.

Programmer Analyst 09/2017 to 04/2019

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd - Chennai, TN, India

- Contributed to spring framework build in Maven and Jenkins to develop RESTful web services which were to be used by America's leading Investor-owned utility.
- Conducted logical analysis of engineering, and other technical problems. Formulated models of solutions.
- Contributed, deployed and maintained various webservices on Heroku as well as EC2/AWS.
- Developed and tested a chatbot for client website on Dialogflow with webhooks running on google firebase.

- Worked on a chatbot for Facebook messenger with webhooks coded in php and running on Heroku.
- Created an automation tool for internal process on UiPath and Automation Anywhere.
- Achieved a global rank of 12 in an internal competition on Java and was given a title of "Orbit Shifter"

Process Analyst 01/2014 to 04/2014

Ecoad – Pune, Maharashtra

- Designed a Java based inventory system which would keep track of profits and stocks.
- Prepared manuals and trained workers to use new stencils for paper bag manufacturing according to organizational policy.
- Designed and devised new methods which increased the production by 10%

Education

Graduate Certificate, Mobile Solutions Development:

May 2019 - Present

Conestoga College - Waterloo, Ontario

- Coursework related to HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Android, iOS and C#
- Scored 3.89 GPA
- Made it to the Dean's honor's list with no subject less than 80%

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science:

August 2012 - May 2017

Pune University - Pune, Maharashtra

• Graduated in top 5% of the class. (GPA: 3.9/4.0, First Class with Distinction)

Co-curricular Activities

Student Volunteer May 2019

Conestoga College - Waterloo

- Organized and contributed towards various in-house events under student engagement section
- Helped international students for onboarding them on their new semester.

Student Representative May 2019

Conestoga College – Waterloo

- Student representative of my course (Mobile Solutions Development)
- Represented students for their betterment in college and resolved their queries and problems.
- Numerous suggestions given for betterment of campus and surroundings.

Student Technology Squad

December 2013 to August 2016

- Contributed as team leader for Software department of the college ROBOCON 2015 Team.
 - Responsibilities included developing a native code running on Arduino and capable of handling wireless requests and move robot accordingly.
- Facilitated various lectures for freshmen and sophomore students in computer hardware and software focusing mainly on android and embedded systems.

• Conducted workshops under "Train the Teacher" initiative by institute.

Curricular Activities

- Participated in various hackathons while with previous employer, represented my department in the pool of 100+ participants and stood out as an outstanding achiever.
 - Solution proposed An Optimised internal dashboard tool on SpringBoot for managing and testing various webservices at once